Gonçalo Cardoso Curriculum Vitae

Javascript Developer & Evangelist

Personal Info

Full Name Gonçalo Cardoso Borges Ferreira

Date of Birth 7th August 1989

Nationality Portuguese

Phone 00351 91 857 17 46

Email & Website goncalo.cb.ferreira@gmail.com / www.gcardoso.pt

Summary

About me

I'm an enthusiastic Javascript developer with a big passion for web and software development. I'm very professional with a great work ethic and a loyal worker that focuses on the best results. I have a powerful team spirit, a creative mind and a great sense of humour. Technically, I code not only with native object oriented Javascript but I also have experience working with many frameworks and libraries, such as AngularJS, React and jQuery. My front-end development approach follows the SEO rules and techniques as well as usability guidelines with performance awareness. The mobile compatibility is one of my main concerns so I'm always focused on making my applications work nice and smoothly on mobile devices. Given my passion about javascript, I'm also a co-organizer of a very well known and recognised javascript meetup in Lisbon, called require('lx').

Work Experience

Date March 2015 to present

Company e.near - Nearshore Technology Solutions Computer Software House

Position held Lead Javascript Developer

Address Lisbon, Portugal

Main responsibilities I'm responsible for the development of mobile casino games, using mainly Javascript

for the frontend (2D Canvas & WebGL), backend (Node.js) and unit testing. As a team leader of a 10 people team, my main goal is to motivate and push them to deliver high quality games, taking the responsibility of all the technical decisions made in the process. As a javascript specialist within the company, I'm also responsible for mentoring and teaching all the other developers who work for other projects, to make sure they follow high quality code standards. I encourage the entire company to be aware about the cutting edge technologies by attending conferences and meetups.

Core skills developed Algorithms and Data Structures, Unit Testing, Software Engineering, Project

Management, Functional Programming, Test Driven Development, Object Oriented

Programming, Team Leadership, Quality Assurance, Games Development

Date October 2013 to March 2015

Company StepValue - Web Intelligence Digital Marketing Agency

Position held Front-end Engineer

Address Lisbon, Portugal

Main responsibilities I was responsible for the front-end development of desktop and mobile web

applications, always focused on user experience, design, performance and responsive techniques, using the latest frameworks by that time, such as Angular JS and Kendo UI. Most of the web applications were single-page apps and the front-end was consumed by REST Api's, which required an asynchronous development approach. Given my passion for programming and software engineering, I worked very closely with the backend developers and that pushed me to apply the same object oriented

programming standards in my javascript code.

Core skills developed Software Engineering, Object Oriented Programming, Web Development, Digital

Marketing, System Analysis, Database Design, Web Services Architecture (REST),

Customer Relations

Date October 2010 to October 2013

Company Portugal Telecom Information and Communication Technologies

Position held Front-end Developer

Address Lisbon, Portugal

Main responsibilities I was responsible for the front-end development of desktop and mobile websites,

always focused on user experience, design, performance and responsive techniques using HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript. In addition, I was also concerned about cross-

browser compatibility, including the old ones like Internet Explorer 7.

I've worked with major portuguese clients such as Sport Lisboa e Benfica, Portugal Telecom, Portuguese Football Federation and Portuguese Navy. In the last two projects, besides developing my role was to lead the front-end team. It was in

Portugal Telecom that I learned how important it is to strictly structure your code and

follow the standards.

Core skills developed Object Oriented Programming, Web Development, User Experience, Web Design,

Team Leadership, Customer Relations, Animation and Video

Date February 2008 to August 2008

Company Finepaper Graphic Design and Production

Position held Web developer - Part-time

Address Lisbon, Portugal

Main responsibilities While I was studying, I tried to find an opportunity that could help me putting in

practice what I was learning in college, and Finepaper gave me that chance. I was responsible for the development of flash websites using the programming language

ActionScript 3.0, including the company's website.

Core skills developed Web Development, Programming

Education

Date October 2007 to July 2010

Course Multimedia Engineering

Degree Bachelor (Bologna Process)

Institution Instituto Superior de Tecnologias Avançadas

Final grade 15 / 20

Main subjects Software Engineering, Programming Languages, Web Development, Database Design

and Management, Data Structures, Maths and Statistics, Management, Encryption and

Security, Video and Animation

Main Skills

Development HTML5, CSS3, Javascript ES6 (Functional, Modular and Object Oriented), Node.js,

Single Page Applications, Progressive Enhancement, Graceful Degradation, Cross-

browser Compatibility, 2D Canvas, WebGL, Flux & Redux, Git & SVN

APIs REST APIs, Facebook Graph API, Google Maps API, Twitter API

Javascript frameworks React, AngularJS, Kendo UI, jQuery (UI and Mobile)

Testing frameworks Mocha, Cha, Selenium

Soft skills Enthusiasm, creativity, problem solving, teamwork, decision making, quick learning,

time management, team leadership, determination, responsibility, patience,

proactivity, accuracy, result-driven

Interests Swimming, walking, running, music, digital world, advertising, marketing, politics,

design, web development, programming, computer science, tech conferences and

meetups